

Suman Kanti Roy

- ★ Kolkata, West Bengal
- roy.sumankanti@gmail.com
- +91 7411940354
- https://s-kroy.github.io/ux/

Technical Tools

Adobe XD	0	0	•
Figma	0	0	
Photoshop	0	0	
Illustrator	0	0	
InDesign	0		0
After Effects	0		0
HTML & CSS	0		0
VS Code	0		0
Bootstrap		0	0
Power BI	•	0	0
Regioner Advanced			



"With great power...comes great responsibility"

Stan Lee

Marvel Comics

Writer | Editor | Publisher | Producer

Professional Profile

I'm a creative professional who loves to paint on canvas & touch-screen surfaces. I do both user experience design & user interface design for interactive products, digital services & enterprise solutions. I simply try to connect the dots between human vision with machine algorithms by applying design methodology and accessibility principles. I have 10+ years of diversified design experience across multiple domains for start-ups and leading corporate brands. I am always keen to learn new-age tech & soft skills to harness my problem-solving ability.

Academic Education

Bachelor of Visual Arts

Govt. College of Art & Craft, Tripura University Drawing & Painting | 2006 - 2010

Bachelor of Science

Maharaja Bir Bikram College, Tripura University Mathematics I 2004 - 2006

Employment History

17 Jan 2022 — till date

Lexmark International India Pvt. Ltd.

Usability Design Engineer

17 Mar 2017 — 15 Jan 2022
Wipro Limited
Senior UI & UX Designer

11 Mar 2015 — 15 Mar 2017

RxPrism Health Systems Pvt. Ltd.

Creative UI & UX Designer

06 Jan 2014 — 20 Feb 2015 Hibu India Pvt. Ltd.
Graphic & Web Designer

15 Apr 2013 — 30 Dec 2013

Bid & Hammer Fine Art Auctioneer

Visual Designer & Researcher

Certificate & Credentials

- Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner badge issued by IBM.
- Understanding Augmented Reality in Business from Skillsoft.
- Adobe XD Essentials assessment and training issued by Adobe.
- Certificate of Completion on Html-5, Css-3 & Sass from Udemy.
- Certificate of Completion on Bootstrap-4 from Udemy.

Rewards & Recognition

- "Lexmark Chief Technology Officer Award 2022" for AR techbased retail shopping app in the Focus-2-Future, a yearly event.
- Wipro Top Gear Crowdsourcing Challenge Award for the "Digital micro prioritisation Interface" project in 2020 from Wipro Digital.
- Recognise badge credentials & 1,000 \$ rewards from Wipro on completion of training & assignment Adobe XD Essentials 2019.
- Appreciation from renowned movie Director "Atanu Ghosh" for making a logo for "Satyajit Ray Film Society Bengaluru" in 2017.
- Win the "Excellent Creative Professional Award 2015" organised by Rxprism Health System Pvt. Ltd. on World Environment Day.
- "Sumangol Sen Memorial Scholarship" for painting category from Govt. College of Arts and Craft, Agartala, Tripura in 2010.